let's look at the solution to our full
sharing quiz we have two blocks a block
that has a B C and D in it and the block
that has X Y Z and W in it we're looking
for which of these if any have for
sharing misses so let's first look at
this one there is a read X and the write
X the first will be a Miss the second
will also be a Miss both of these are
compulsory misses X wasn't in c0 s cache
X wasn't in C ones cache so they have to
be compulsory misses a read a here is
also a compulsory miss this block wasn't
in c2s cache finally c3 is writing to be
this block wasn't in see trees cache so
this is also a compulsory miss so in
fact this sequence has no coherence
misses whatsoever all of them are
compulsory misses now let's look here
this is a compulsory miss for c0 this is
a compulsory miss for c1 this is a
compulsory miss for c2 and this is a
compulsory miss to c3 so regardless
whether we had coherence or not these
four accesses would be misses because
each of these caches needs to fetch the
block for the first time so there are no
coherence misses in this sequence either
now let's look here c0 reads X c1 writes
to X this invalidates X in C 0 this
invalidation needs to happen in order
for X to be written in C 1 C 2 now
writes to W that invalidates the data in
see once cache the data and sees zeros
cache was already invalidated at that
point when C 0 tries to read X the
reason it doesn't have the data in its
cache is because C 1 invalidated it and
c1 was accessing the same word so this
is an example of true sharing
we got invalidated because somebody was
trying to write the same world that we
were accessing so this is actually a
sequence of three compulsory misses
followed by a true sharing coherence
miss so in this sequence there is also
no false sharing so none of these should
have been selected